Amanjot Singh

MERN stack developer having 3 years of experience in developing web applications using MERN stack, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Sql and other util libraries. Seeking a challenging position as a JavaScript developer.

Delhi, India amandhunna.dev@gmail.com +91-7042458977

Github | Linkedin

EXPERIENCE

Kivi Health (Jio health hub), Gurugram—Software engineer

September 2020 - Present

Kivihealth is a platform to manage doctor and patient data and services.

- Architected, planned and improved the file structure for the React applications (Doctor app and Admin app) using functional components and hooks to reduce the development time and improved performance by 2x times using shareable components and dynamic imports.
- Enforced code quality by PR reviews (using <u>Airbnb guidelines</u>)
 and improved performance by moving heavy tasks to cloud
 functions in the backend and fixing memory leak issues in the
 frontend.
- Implemented OOPs in util of the express and React app to reduce the code base by 2x times.

Tech Stack: Express, React, SQL, Redis, HTML, CSS

Successive Technologies, Noida — Associate software engineer

July 2018 - September 2020

Successive Technologies is a service based company.

Project 1: Maketcube.io

A Complete multi-vendor management solution for vendor onboarding, inventory, order splitting, shipping, fulfilment and vendor payouts.

- Developed the web builder using react, html and css. A drag and drop based profile builder to create portfolios, this launched as a premium feature of the product.
- Improved design system by implementing the Storybook.
- Imported rest apis to the GraphQL to reduce over-fetching and under-fetching of the applications.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python,

HTML, CSS

Frontend: React, Apollo

Backend: Express, Redis,

GraphQL

Databases: MongoDB, SQL

Cloud: AWS (lambda)

Version Control: Git

EDUCATION

Engineering Fellow

2021 - Present

Pesto

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology, New Delhi, INDIA

2014 - 2018

<u>Guru Tegh Bahadur</u> <u>Institute of Technology</u>

Tech Stack: Express, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, HTML, CSS

Client 1: Cien.ai

Helps companies to increase sales using AI on their Data

- Implemented Custom bar chart from Chart.js by modifying Chart.js library functions.
- Developed the lambda function for heavy computational tasks.
- Implemented Data exports as pdf functionality using pure HTML/CSS and javascript.

Tech Stack: Express, Meteor, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

PROJECTS

Project 1: Little Tags

Proiect | Github

- At Pesto developed this application using React and Node to emulate online shopping experience.
- The state based approached used to design react components to keep application in the predictable states only.

Tech Stack: Express, React, Firestore, HTML, CSS

Project 2: MyShop

Project | Frontend | Backend

- A Full-Stack React and Node application to emulate online shopping experience.
- Implemented to practice and extend knowledge of React, Express and MongoDB.

Tech Stack: Express, React, MongoDB, HTML, CSS